Guide to the Donald Crossley Vining Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Donald Crossley Vining papers
1926-1997
MS 524
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.38
The papers consist of the diaries of Donald Crossley Vining for the years 1932-1958 and for 1971-1985, as well as typed transcripts from his diaries for 1926-1927. The diaries provide a detailed account of the life of an intellectual, homosexual man in the 1940s and 1950s. Vining, who spent most of his adult life in New York, took a great interest in the arts, and his diaries contain descriptions of operas and plays which he attended; outlines of his current writing projects and theater activities; and details of his daily life and personal relationships. Typescripts of several one and two act plays are included in the papers.
Vining, Donald, 1917-1998
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Donald Vining, 1959-1960; gift of the Estate of Donald Vining, 1998-2000.
Associated Materials
Donald Vining diaries, 1959-1970, are located at the American Heritage Center, University of Wyoming.
Arrangement
Arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
Donald Crossley Vining was born on June 20, 1917, in Benton, Pennsylvania. He was educated at West Chester State College, Pennsylvania and at the Yale University School of Drama. In the late 1940s, he published numerous one-act plays for amateurs. Vining worked in the Development Office of Teachers College, Columbia University for thirty years, retiring in 1979 to begin a private publishing company, The Pepys Press, which specialized in diaries and journals. He published the autobiographical work, A Gay Diary. After retiring from publishing, Vining did free-lance writing for gay periodicals and a monthly column for Diarist's Journal. He died on January 24, 1998, in New York City.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of the diaries of Donald Crossley Vining for the years 1932-1958 and for 1971-1985, as well as typed transcripts from his diaries for 1926-1927. The diaries provide a detailed account of the life of an intellectual, homosexual man in the 1940s and 1950s. Vining, who spent most of his adult life in New York, took a great interest in the arts, and his diaries contain descriptions of operas and plays which he attended; outlines of his current writing projects and theater activities; and details of his daily life and personal relationships. Typescripts of several one and two act plays are included in the papers.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Gay men -- United States; Homosexuality; Music; Theater; New York (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs; New York (State); Diaries; Actors; Authors; LGBTQ resource; Vining, Donald, 1917-1998
- Inventory
  - Diaries
    - 1926-1937 Apr (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
    - 1937 May-1941 (Box 2, Folder 12-25)
    - 1942-1946 Aug (Box 3, Folder 26-39)
    - 1946 Sep-1952 Jun (Box 4, Folder 40-53)
    - 1952 Jul-1958 (Box 5, Folder 54-66)
- Additional Material, Accession 1999-M-067
  - Diaries
    - 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1-10)
    - 1976-1980 (Box 2, Folder 11-20)
    - 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 21-30)
- Additional Material, Accession 1999-M-103
  - Plays [typescripts of one and two act plays], n.d.
    - "Kin" (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "The Poor Dear" (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Top Men" (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Twosomes" (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Additional Material, Accession 2001-M-006
  - Diaries
    - 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
    - 1992-1997 (Box 2, Folder 7-12)